{"id":"2017_13","name":"Romans2017_13","memoryVerse":"“What a wretched man I am! Who will rescue me from this body that is subject to death? Thanks be to God, who  delivers me through Jesus Christ our Lord!” – Romans 7:24-25a","dayQuestions":{"one":{"title":"FIRST DAY: Read the notes and the references.","questions":[{"id":"2017_13_1","questionText":"1. What was meaningful to you in the lecture?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_13_2","questionText":"2. What help did you receive from the notes?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"two":{"title":"SECOND DAY: Read Romans 8:1-4.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"8:1-4"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_13_3a","questionText":"3. a.  From your study of Romans 1-7, how would you explain Romans 8:1? What is the significance of “now” and “no condemnation”? (For additional help, see John 3:16-17; 5:24.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"8:1"},{"book":"John","verse":"3:16-17"},{"book":"John","verse":"5:24"}]},{"id":"2017_13_3b","questionText":"3. b. How does Romans 8:1 affect the way you view yourself and others? What changes will you ask God to make in your thoughts or actions?","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"8:1"}]},{"id":"2017_13_4","questionText":"4.  How does this passage show that the whole Trinity (Father, Son and Holy Spirit) works to save sinners? ","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_13_5","questionText":"5.  Because those in Christ are no longer under law, why and how do they fulfill the law’s righteous requirements?  (See also John 14:15-21; 16:5-15.) ","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"John","verse":"14:15-21"},{"book":"John","verse":"16:5-15"}]}]},"three":{"title":"THIRD DAY: Read Romans 8:5-11.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"8:5-11"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_13_6","questionText":"6.  Name the two basic groups of people these verses describe and contrast their mindsets and lives.","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_13_7","questionText":"7.  How can you recognize a mind set on what the Spirit desires? (See also Galatians 5:22-23; Colossians 3:1-4.) Would others say that is true of you? ","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Galatians","verse":"5:22-23"},{"book":"Colossians","verse":"3:1-4"}]},{"id":"2017_13_8","questionText":"8.  According to verses 9-11, what things are true of everyone in whom the Spirit of God (also called the Spirit of Christ) lives, and how do these truths encourage you today?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"four":{"title":"FOURTH DAY: Read Romans 8:12-14.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"8:12-14"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_13_9","questionText":"9.  According to these verses, what is a Christian’s obligation and why? (See also 2 Corinthians 7:1; Philippians  3:10-14; 1 John 3:1-3.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"2 Corinthians","verse":"7:1"},{"book":"Philippians","verse":"3:10-14"},{"book":"1 John","verse":"3:1-3"}]},{"id":"2017_13_10a","questionText":"10. a.  How can God’s children “put to death the misdeeds of the body”? (See also Galatians 5:13-26; Colossians 3:5-17.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Galatians","verse":"5:13-26"},{"book":"Colossians","verse":"3:5-17"}]},{"id":"2017_13_10b","questionText":"10. b.  What does the phrase “put to death” teach about the attitude God’s children are to have toward their sin, and where do you need the Holy Spirit’s help to change your attitude and actions?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"five":{"title":"FIFTH DAY: Read Romans 8:14-17.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"8:14-17"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_13_11","questionText":"11.  List privileges of adoption into God’s family. (See also Romans 8:29.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"8:29"}]},{"id":"2017_13_12","questionText":"12.   From the following verses, give additional benefits of being God’s child and, if you are a believer, express how you have experienced these benefits.  (Matthew 6:7-8; 10:29-31; Hebrews 12:7-11; 1 John 3:1-3) ","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Matthew","verse":"6:7-8"},{"book":"Matthew","verse":"10:29-31"},{"book":"Hebrews","verse":"12:7-11"},{"book":"1 John","verse":"3:1-3"}]},{"id":"2017_13_13","questionText":"13.  How might these truths help you or others who struggle with doubt of God’s fatherly love?    ","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"six":{"title":"SIXTH DAY: Review Romans 8:1-17.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"8:1-17"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_13_14","questionText":"14.  What have you learned about God in this week’s study? How may your group pray for you as you make this truth a part of your life?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_13_15","questionText":"15. Homiletics for group and administrative leaders: Romans 8:1-17","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"8:1-17"}]}]}}}